敵だ！
It's the enemy!
来たぞ！！
They're coming!
（シカマル）まったく…
これじゃ　キリがねえぜ。
Damn it, there's no end to them.
ただ　ただ消耗していく…
いつまで続くんだ？
They're just wearing us out.
How long is this going
to continue?
うん？　雨…。
Rain?
天気雨…。
≪別方向から敵！！
It's raining while sunny?
The enemy is coming from
a different direction!
《白いのとは違う。
アイツも穢土転生？》
He's not one of those white guys...
Was he reanimated too?
泣いてる？
Is he crying?
子供にも見えるが…
チッ…　戦争ってやつかよ！
He looks like a child.
But this is a war, after all!
なんだ…　この雨は…。
What's with this rain?
くっ…　うっ…。
（スクイ）サクラ！　入るわよ。
I'm coming in, Sakura!
（サクラ）はい。
Okay!
そこの台にお願いします。
（スクイ）よろしく。
Place him on that table!
（スクイ）次！
はい！
Take care of this.
– We're moving on to the next one!
– Okay!
（サクラ）あなた…　誰？
Who are you?
フフフ…　フフフフフ…。
なに？
What's going on?
雪？
Snow?
ちょ…　何してんの！
Hey... What are you doing?
♪♪「コン　コン　コン　雪だコン
コン　コン　コン　雪だコン」
Kon, kon, kon...
It's snowing, kon...
It's snowing, kon.
Kon, kon, kon...
えっ…　えっ…。
Huh?
What?!
（サクラ）え～っ！？
うっ…。
（シノ）蟲玉！
Beetle Sphere!
（キバ）牙通牙！
Fang Over Fang!
（キバ）赤丸！
（赤丸）ワン　ワン！
Akamaru!
クソ…　雷遁か？
Damn it! Lightning Style, huh?!
ワン！　ワン　ワン！
（キバ）誰かいる。
Someone's there!
ワン　ワン！　ワン　ワン！
お前　知ってるのか？
Do you know who it is?
プン　プン　プン…。
プン　プン　プン！
怒ってるのか？
ワン　ワン！
Is he angry?
うわっ！！
（ナルト）みんな…　待ってろよ。
Hold on, everyone!
softness can overcome hardness, but hardness can overcome softness
juuyokugou wo seishimashite gouyokujuu motatsu
if you're too focused on showing off, my alarm will go off
muchuu de kakkou tsukete mo hijou beru ga naru
walk fifty steps forward in a reckless style
gojuuppo ijou mo saki aruite chottotsumoushinna sutairu
you're moody and do as you please; no matter what I do, you ignore me
jiyuu de kibunya no kimi wa douyattatte mushi
there's a mystery that no one can solve, I shiver when the wind blows
darenimo tokenai nazo ga aru fukidashita kaze ni furueteru
I'll unravel this maze
kono meiro wo hodoite yaru
you laughed, will it rain tomorrow?
kimi ga waratta ashita wa ame kai
the wise light flickers
soumeina hikari ga chikachika hikaru
you've got to focus your eyes before the future changes
me wo korasanakucha mirai ga kawatte shimau mae ni
I'm sure, I'm sure this moment will be swept away
kitto kitto ima wo saratte iku
I have to be with you, otherwise the future might dry up
kimi to janakucha mirai wa kawaite shimau no kamo
hurry up, because I'm sure that we'll smile back on this moment
isoge kitto ima wo waratte iku
Rain Followed by Snow, with Some Lightning
（チョウザ）なんだ？　あの雨。
What was that rain?
（ダルイ）新手の敵っすかね？
だるいっす。
Do you think it's a new enemy?
How tiresome...
（シカマル）くっ！
うぅ…。
（チョウジ）倍化の術！
Expansion Jutsu!
チョウジ！
（いの）シカマル！
Choji!
Shikamaru!
すまねえ　いの…。
Sorry, Ino!
影首縛りの術！
Shadow Strangle Jutsu!
成功。
Complete!
（３人）うわ～！
縛ってんのに　どうして　術を！？
How can he still use jutsu
while he's bound?
（いの）ちょ…　これって！
Hey... This is...
くっ！　印が…。
My sign!
なんなの！？　この雨！
あぁ…。
What's with this rain?
（チョウジ）動けない…。
I can't move.
クソ！
Damn it.
シカマル！　チョウジ！　いの！
Shikamaru, Choji, Ino...
It's me!
私だよ。
コイツ…　なんで　私たちの名前を？
How does he know our names?!
僕　知らないよ　こんなヤツ。
I don't know him.
俺もだよ。　うっ！
Me neither.
What?!
なっ！
イタッ！
うわっ！
Ouch!
雪だ　コン！
えっ？
It's snowing, kon.
What?
イテッ！
Ouch!
お前…。
アンタ！
You're...
そうか！
ワン　ワン！
I remember...
ヨタ！
（２人）ヨタ！
Yota!
– Yota!
ヨタ！
Yota!
《シカマル：ヨタ…　そうだ！
俺たちは　お前を知っている》
Yota...
That's right... We know you.
((ここらへんだと思うんだけど。
I think it's around here.
大事なクナイのセットなのに…
どうしよう？
It's a precious kunai set.
What'll I do?
クナイなんて　投げるもんなんだから
なくなんのは　しかたねえだろ？
Kunai are meant for throwing,
so it can't be helped
if you lose them.
だって　あれは
アカデミーに入った記念に→
But my mom bought them for me
母ちゃんに買ってもらったんだよ。
as a reward for getting into
the Academy!
なくしちゃったら
母ちゃんが悲しむよ…。
If I lose them,
my mom's going to be sad.
チョウジは優しい子なんだから
つきあってあげるの！
Choji is a nice kid,
so we're going to help him out.
はぁ…　面倒くせぇな。
What a pain.
僕のクナイ…。
My kunai.
ったく…　どこへ投げたんだよ？
Damn it,
where did you throw them?
ないわね…。
I can't find it.
あっ！
雨…。
Huh?
あれ！？　おかしいな？
Rain...
Huh? That's odd.
天気なのに…。
It's sunny too.
ん！？
な…　なんだ！？　ありゃ！
何？
W-What is that?!
What?
えっ！？　ちょ…　あれ　人？
Hey...
Is that a person?
あ～っ！
Oh!
僕のクナイだ！
My kunai!
なんだよ？　アイツ…。
僕のクナイが刺さってるよ。
What's wrong with him?
My kunai are stuck on him!
どうやったら　あんなとこに…。
How did it get there?!
とにかく　行こうぜ！
うん！
Anyway, let's go.
Yeah.
僕のクナイ！
My kunai!
情けないわね！
How pathetic.
木登りの術なんて
まだ　教わってねえよ…。
I still haven't learned
the Tree Climbing Jutsu yet,
親父たちみたいに
スタコラ登れるかっての！
so I can't climb it
as easily as our dads.
でも…　大事なクナイが！
But my precious kunai!
（チョウジ／シカマル）あぁ～！
キャーッ！
クソーッ！
Damn it.
うわ～っ！
シカマル　チョウジ！
Shikamaru! Choji!
え　ちょ　ちょっと　うわ～っ！
Hey, wait.
チョウジ！
Choji!
（ヨタ）ぴったんこ　アハッ！
Good-good!
Huh?
アハハハッ…。
アハハハハッ…。
雨が…。
やんだ。
The rain...
It stopped.
（チョウジ／ヨタ）アハハハハッ。
(ん？))
WEATHER FOR SALE
ヨタなんだろ　お前。
You're Yota, aren't you?
ヨタ　思い出した。
Yota... I remember!
そうだよ　なんで　今まで…。
That's right...
How could we forget!
ヨタ　お前も穢土転生。
えっ？
Yota... You're a Reanimation...
コイツも…。
What?
Him too?
（３人）うわ～っ！
そうだ　ヨタは天気を操ることが。
That's right...
Yota can control the weather.
ヨタ　やめてくれよ！
Yota... Please stop!
うわ～っ！
ヨタの意思じゃねえよ。
ヨタは　操られて。
Yota's not doing it on purpose.
He's being controlled.
じゃあ　ヨタはもう…。
Then that means that
Yota is already...
((私　ヨタ。
ヨタ？
Me... Yota.
名前？
うん！
Yota? Is that your name?
私って　女かよ。
男だよ。
Yeah.
You're a girl?
I'm a boy.
男で　私かよ。
そうだよ　私は私。
You're a boy who talks like a girl?
That's right. I'm me.
お前　木ノ葉のもんじゃないよな。
You're not from the Leaf are you?
私　違うよ。
どっから来たの？
I'm different.
Where did you come from?
ん？　いろいろなところから。
From all over the place.
いろいろって　国は？
ない。
From all over?
What nation are you from?
里は？
ないよ。
Nowhere.
What village?
アハハハッ　ないよ　ないない！
I don't have one.
I have none, none, none.
ウフフフッ　アハハハッ。
ひとりぼっちなのかな？
どうやら　そうみてえだな。
I wonder if he's lonely.
It sure seems like it.
どうする？
里の大人たちに知らせたほうが。
What should we do?
We should let the adults
in the village know.
ダメだよ。
え？
We can't.
知らない人が入り込んで
この前だって→
There was a big fuss
not too long ago
大騒ぎしたじゃないか。
about a stranger coming in.
今は　里と里が
すごいピチピチしてるって→
My dad said that there's big-big
trouble between the villages.
父ちゃんが言ってた。　だから…。
そうだよな。　ヨタみてえなヤツが
今　里に現れたら。
That's right.
If someone like Yota
showed up in the village...
– Hmm...
ピチピチ　ヒャハハハ。
Big-big.
あ？
ピチピチ。　フハハハ。
Big-big.
チョウジは　ピチピチしてるね。
You're pretty big-big, huh, Choji?
え！？
Huh?
ピチピチというより　ポッチャリかな？
I'm not really big,
but just chubby.
デブデブしてる。
You're a fatty-fatso.
ぼ…　ぼ…　僕は→
I-I'm... n-not a fatso!
デ…　デ…　デブじゃな～い！
まずい！
This is bad!
ん～！
フハ　フハハハハ。
待て！
Come back!
この！
Why you...
ヨタ？　どうしたの？
Yota?
What's wrong?
私のお腹　スカスカ…。
My stomach is empty-empty.
お腹？　ハハハ…。
ハハハ。
Stomach?
へへっ　うまそうに食べてやがる。
He looks like he's enjoying it.
うん！
うらやましい。
Yeah.
I'm so jealous.
もっと。
もう　ねえよ。
More!
There isn't anymore.
贅沢だよ　ヨタ。
You're asking too much of us, Yota.
私　お腹減ってる。
グウグウする。　もっと　もっと！
I'm starving.
It's growling. More, more.
無理言わないの！
Don't ask the impossible.
もういっちょ　もういっちょ
もういっちょ！
One more, one more, one more!
しつこい！
Stop that!
うわぁ～ん。
泣かないの！
Don't cry!
うわぁ～　あぁ～。
ええ！？
また　天気雨。
It's raining again while sunny.
待てよ　さっきもヨタが泣いて…。
Wait... Yota was crying earlier too.
もう泣かない！
Hey! Stop crying!
いのがいじめる。
うわ！
Ino is picking on me...
ヨタが泣くから　雨が降ってるのか？
It's raining because
Yota is crying...
グスッ　わかるよ。
I understand.
僕　ポッチャリ系だから
ヨタの気持　すっごくわかる。
I'm chubby, so I really understand
how Yota feels.
僕まで　お腹減った。
I'm feeling hungry too.
ごめんね　ヨタ。
私が言いすぎた。
Sorry, Yota. I went too far.
どうなってんだ。
なんでお前らまで？
What's going on?
Why are you guys crying too?
悲しくねえのに　悲しいんだ。
I'm not even sad.
But I feel sad.
(ヨタから　もらい泣きかよ))
We caught the crying from Yota?
ヨタ。
Yota...
ヨタ…。
ヨタ！　僕たちは
お前と戦いたくなんかないんだよ。
Yota... We don't want to fight you!
アンタもそうなんでしょ？
You don't want to
fight either, right?
きっとそうだよ　ヨタだもん。
I'm sure that he doesn't.
It's Yota!
わかってんだろ
こいつはヨタの意思なんかじゃねえ。
Don't you understand?
Yota isn't in control here.
アスマのときと同じだ。
It's the same thing,
like what happened with Asuma!
穢土転生…　くそっ！
Damn Reanimation Jutsu!
ヨタ！
Yota...
（サクラ）ヨタ！
デコ！
Yota!
Forehead!
ヘヘヘッ！
ヨタ…。
Yota...
♪♪「コン　コン　コン　雪だコン
コン　コン　コン　雪だコン」
Kon, kon, kon...
It's snowing, kon...
また雪？
The snow's started again.
♪♪「コン　コン　コン　雪だコン
コン　コン　コン　雪だコン」
Kon kon kon...
It's snowing, kon.
♪♪「コン　コン　コン　雪だコン」
Kon kon kon...
It's snowing, kon.
ヨタ…。
– Kon kon kon... It's snowing, kon.
– Yota...
楽しいんだね。
– Kon kon kon... It's snowing, kon.
– You're having fun.
♪♪「コン　コン　コン」
Kon, kon, kon...
((ヨタ？
ヨタ！
Yota!
あっ！
（シカマル）ヨタ！
Yota!
（チョウジ）僕たちだよ。
寝てたら起きて！
It's us!
If you're asleep, then wake up!
（３人）ヨタ！
– Yota!
シカマル　チョウジ　いの！
Shikamaru! Choji! Ino!
んっ　ん～　デコ！
Forehead!
えっ！？　わっ…　わっ　あぁ！
あっ　オメエは！
Hey, you're...
あっ…　あっ！
Oh? Oh!
イタタ…。
Ow ow...
サクラ！
あっ…　あっ！
Sakura...
Oh! Oh!
デコ！
えっ？
Forehead!
What?
キャハ！　アハハハハ！　ハハハハ！
雪？
Snow...
(晴れてるのに…。
天気…　雪？))
But it's sunny...
Snow when it's sunny?
♪♪「コン　コン　コン　雪だコン」
Kon kon kon...
It's snowing, kon.
うっ…。
♪♪「コン　コン　コン　雪やコン
コン　コン　コン　雪やコン」
Kon kon kon...
It's snowing, kon.
ヨタ…。
Yota...
うわぁ～ん！
（キバ）ヨタ！
Yota...
あれは…。
That's...
I was tired of walking and didn't know what I should do
aruki tsukarete tohou ni kureta
my teacher told me to go towards a bright future
akarui mirai e sensei wa iu kedo
but which way should I go to find the light?
docchi ni aruitara hikari wa sasu kana
I have no idea at the moment so let's go
toriaezu wakaranai kedo ikouze
don't tell me things I want to hear
kirei goto nanka maji kan kanben desu
just give me something so powerful that it hurts
itai kurai tsuyoi yatsu wo choudai
I'm rebelling against the ordinary life
arikitari na mainichi ni hankou desu
burning up the mic with our rock
tagire m i c oretachi no rock
I can hear you are screaming
kimino koe ga kikoeru
that's the only thing that's real, let it explode
sore dake wa real sa hajikero
this song
kono uta
i can hear you are screaming
I'm running through the night on impulse
tsuki ugokasare shoudou no mama ni yoru wo kakenda
can't you see can't you see can't you see my face
I want to sense this moment not just the words, I want to sense you
kotoba ja nai ima dake wo kanjitetai kimi wo kanjitetai
i can hear you are screaming
keep on shouting and open the door to tomorrow
sakebi tsuzukete ashita no tobira wo kojihirakerunda
don't worry don't worry don't worry baby
I want to believe in us, not anyone else, I want to believe in my dream
dareka ja nai oretachi wo shinjitetai yume wo shinjitetai
So does this mean
we have to fight Yota?
皆様　お変わりございませんか？
It's just like the time
with Asuma.
美空ひばりです。
We have to fight him
to seal him.
では最後まで　ごゆっくり→
But how are we going to?
お楽しみください。
How can we defeat someone
who controls weather?
How would I know?
（宮本）『木曜８時のコンサート
名曲！にっぽんの歌』。
If I think about it,
we don't know anything about Yota!
（松丸）今回は　ご覧の豪華な歌手
１１組の皆さんによる→
Next time on Naruto Shippuden:
"The Sad Sun Shower"
華麗なステージをお届けいたします。
How sad!
皆さんどうぞ
よろしくお願いいたします。